<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Taleisin - Adventure Machine!</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000" />
<updated>2019-08-22T14:51:55+13:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
<author>
  <name></name>
  <uri>http://localhost:4000/</uri>
  
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crossing an ocean - part 2]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/crossing-an-ocean-part-2/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/crossing-an-ocean-part-2</id>
  <published>2019-08-22T14:45:35+13:00</published>
  <updated>2019-08-22T14:45:35+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;This is part two of our ocean passage, see part one here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily Annie is smart and suggested that I dig out some clamps as she’s certain
there’s two small G clamps in the tool tray under the work bench. I dug the
clamps out and clamped the box down. I took the panel up on the fore-deck and
tied it down. I squeezed as much 5200 in the gap as I could and smoothed it over
with a Popsicle stick (another important set of tools we added recently to the
toolbox). We left the panel to dry until night fall and brought it down below to
continue curing for the requisite 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned to Annie when the job was done and quite proudly announced that “This
will be one of my top five fixes while at sea!” We had a pretty nice day sailing
and we were starting to enjoy the passage. Unfortunately it didn’t last too
long, the next day we were actually sailing in decent weather but the barometer
was steadily dropping. That night things had built up to the point where we had
two small (not big enough to eat) squid wash up on the side deck. The seas were
also so confused that I couldn’t get the wind-vane to steer Taleisin and instead
had to hand steer for two hours before things finally settled enough for the
vane to work again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I’m starting to master the wind-vane, it’s a fine balance of sail trim,
the right tension on the control line and in some cases the use of a bungy cord
on the tiller, which also might need more tension to either port or starboard.
It’s a delicate dance, but something I think is becoming instinctive to me now.
This is the first time we’ve used the wind-vane in anger on passage and I was
surprised that I managed to get it to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things kept building until mid day the following day. We noticed that some of
the sail cars on the mainsail was detached and decided to heave to so we can
re-attach them. I started lashing the cars back on, Annie said, look up. The top
three cars we undone. We would have to hoist the trys’l if we wanted to have
a chance to fix these! We dropped the main, hoisted the trys’l and put Taleisin
back in the hove to position. I started lashing the sail cars back on as best as
I could. While in this position it became pretty obvious to us that we’d have to
get the para-anchor out soon. We set to task and we were very glad we did it
when we thought about it. Within an hour of setting the para-anchor things got
serious. The swells increased to five meters (imagine staring at a ten meter
wall of water when you’re at the bottom). On top of those swells were one and
a half meter breaking waves. We have no way of knowing the exact wind speed but
using the Beaufort scale and our observations we estimate the winds to have been
around forty to fifty knots. It was certainly a lot more wind than we’d ever
been in and we know for certain that we had sailed in thirty five knots gusting
forty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point we sent Bob a message and told him we were forced to heave to, his
reply was, stay hove to until morning, then sail to a way point north east. We
intended to do just that. Through the night I didn’t get up enough to check on
our gear and the anchor rode had managed to chafe quite badly. This was due to
the fact that Taleisin tacked on us and the rode was running underneath the bob
stay. I though it would be fine since our bob-stay is basically covered in
a chafe guard. Little did I know that the conditions were so rough that it
actually managed to tear the top part of the guard open and pushed it up so that
the rode would happily chafe against the stainless steel wire. I noticed this
when Taleisin tacked back and we attempted to get the pennant in the right
position to try to avoid tacking. I shorted the scope to the point where I could
inspect the chafe, “Nope, cannot have this out there I don’t trust that it wont
break”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B1Z59veH9q2/&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px;
box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px;
max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%;
width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B1Z59veH9q2/&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center;
text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex;
flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color:
#F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px;
width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column;
flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4;
border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width:
100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px;
flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:
19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px;
width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000,
-20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41
553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852
C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41
556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50
C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114
551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886
524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113
557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101
C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057
562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757
556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552
C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757
523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057
518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101
C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056
516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938
518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654
C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448
541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756
557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894
C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978
565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996
565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258
569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368
562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18
C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18
C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368
516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258
511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147
511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651
C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658
521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965
532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82
C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634
565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743
570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851
570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0;
font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal;
font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row;
margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color:
#F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform:
translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4;
height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px);
width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width:
12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4;
border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px
solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px)
translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid
transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color:
#F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform:
translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px
solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px)
translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0
4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B1Z59veH9q2/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000;
font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal;
font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;
word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;This is what happens if you don’t tend
your anchor rode frequently when you have a para-anchor out in a storm
#fujiframez&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif;
font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px;
overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis;
white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/svtaleisin/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd;
font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal;
font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; Annie Ryan&lt;/a&gt;
(@svtaleisin) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px;
line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-08-20T23:47:39+00:00&quot;&gt;Aug 20, 2019 at 4:47pm
PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately this meant that now we’re on a shortened scope. It was morning and
we were considering hauling the para-anchor in and taking off. We thought we’d
have something to eat first since it was still quite rough sea conditions. After
breakfast we realized that we’re not going anywhere, things kicked up even worse
than the previous night. This time I went and checked the rode more frequently
and dammit, Taleisin tacked again. I kept moving the rode to avoid it chafing as
much but we managed to get another really bad spot of chafe on the rode. This is
crazy, we can’t keep doing this. I know we still have another spare rode under
the work bench but trying to dig that out in these conditions is a bit beyond
what my constitution would allow. We tried the best we could with what we had
and it somehow seemed to work. It was around this time that the first mental
challenges started, Annie had a crisis of confidence and a bit of an emotional
meltdown. Not because she was scared but because everything just seemed to get
to her. I tried to comfort her as best as I could and got on with the tasks at
hand. I recall saying to Annie at one point while everything was in full swing
as we headed up on deck: “It’s do or die out here”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later when people asked us if we were scared or concerned we’d reply with,
there’s no time for that sort of stuff, you just get on with it. Once the
weather cleared we got underway as soon as possible and we sailed Taleisin as
hard as we could. We decided that it was time to push on as fast as we could as
to avoid any more bad weather. Bob gave us a way point to aim for and we made
haste! As we hoisted the mainsail we managed to give the second solar panel we
lashed to the dingy a good crunch. You’d think that we might have learned from
the first time that we should take it down before doing stuff in rougher
weather. Seriously at this point we don’t deserve to have solar panels, we just
don’t seem to take care of them. Luckily it’s only cosmetic, it still works just
as poorly as before. This panel was the first solar panel we bought, it’s a 100
watt Solbian, supposedly the best there is. Well it doesn’t produce much power
any more. We were going to return it since it’s got a pretty long warranty, but
alas it’s now a very expensive souvenir. We certainly don’t have the money to
replace it either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next 24 hours Annie’s loss of confidence started to have a knock on
effect. Every time something got a bit challenging during her watch she’d wake
me up. This is absolutely fine as I’d rather she wake me than get in serious
trouble. Unfortunately it meant that I got hardly any sleep. This quickly lead
to me having a crisis of confidence thinking that we might have made a mistake
coming out onto the open ocean. I started formulating a plan to create a sleep
cycle for myself that will allow us to carry on without completely depleting my
life force. The next morning at around 7 am things kicked up again and we hove
to under trys’l only. I went down below and got some much needed sleep (still in
my foul weather gear on the cabin sole), Annie kept an eye on conditions in case
it got worse. A few hours later we were under way again. I made the decision to
sail under trys’l alone. I put Annie on the helm and got her to hand steer and
learn how to feel the motion of the boat in trickier conditions. She surfed the
waves for a few hours and then she set the wind vane. I’m not sure if this
helped or not but it seemed like her levels of confidence returned to normal
after that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out that upon asking her if she felt better about knowing how the boat
handles, or about knowing what to do in those conditions she said, “I know what
to do, and that wasn’t anything new for me.  It’s just that some things you said
or have done have confused me so far.  I’m now no longer sure my judgment is
correct or if I am letting things go for too long.”  I just want to put on
record that Annie is extremely competent, her loss of confidence was purely due
to the mental challenges we faced. She’s capable of handling the boat on her own
in most conditions. She’s also the best crew mate I could wish for. The mental
challenge while out there is a strange one, and I cannot find the words to
describe it, unless you’ve experienced it for yourself you probably wouldn’t
understand it either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We kept the trys’l up for the rest of the day and night, it proved a good
choice, we were still making good way and the winds and seas were quite variable
such that we were happy to keep going with the sail configuration. It also meant
that I was able to get better sleep due to the fact that I knew the boat was
configured for what ever may come already. All we needed to do to heave to was
sheet the trys’l in, head to wind and tie the tiller off. That’s quick and easy
and either of us can do that alone without any issue.  This also helped get
Annie’s confidence back on track, so it was well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning we put a doubled reefed main and stays’l up which moved us fast
enough and kept the configuration manageable enough so we both felt comfortable
when on watch alone. Unfortunately, it was a bit rocky because of the wind,
swell and chop direction, but the sailing wasn’t too bad so we didn’t complain
much. While sailing along with Annie sleeping in the bunk I heard a bang. It
wasn’t huge since the wind forces wasn’t too high. I popped my head up and saw
the stays’l stay swinging on the port side. “Oh crap, get up Annie, we have to
deal to the stays’l!” I rushed up on deck to investigate. At first I thought we
might have lost the stay somehow (but I inspected it all before we left). Then
I thought that possibly the Highfield lever had undone itself, but that was
still in the closed position. Oh no, did the attachments on the bowsprit rip out
somehow? It couldn’t have there’s not enough wind to do that! I went up forward
to have a look. Nope it’s all still attached. Then I grabbed the sail and
brought it all in, letting the halyard go as I do that to make the whole mess
manageable. Once I had it in hand, I noticed what had happened. The cotter pin,
which has a spring loaded ball bearing to supposedly keep it from doing just
this had come out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bugger! How did I miss that during inspection. Heck I replaced the bit of tired
string that held the cotter pin onto the rest of the assembly (good thing too as
we might have lost it). We worked swiftly to get it all back in place, but we
had an issue with preventing this in the future. Larry, show me the way! I said
to myself. I looked at the cotter pin again and noticed there was a hole drilled
in the other end. The light bulb went on! I need some kind of pin through there!
I looked at the forward hatch and saw a keyring style pin holding the hatch
cotter pin in! That’s it! I removed it from the hatch and applied it to the pin
on the stay! Problem solved. I placed the cotter pin from the hatch in my pocket
since we wont need it until we undo the hatch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went down below to rifle through my rigging bag. There’s bound to be something
in there! Annie made the comment that the rigging bag is like Mary Poppins’
handbag, there’s all kinds of crap in there and it’s almost always the right
kind of usefulness when you need it! I found another keyring style pin and went
to replace the hatch cotter pin right away. By now we’ve learned that if the
opportunity to deal to something exist you do it immediately, it pays for itself
in the future. We were very lucky that this happened during reasonably clam
conditions as it might have done some serious damage otherwise. While it’s
a potential mishap we felt like we dodged a bullet here. We got lucky!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be concluded…&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/crossing-an-ocean-part-2/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Crossing an ocean - part 2 here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on August 22, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The post most of you have been waiting for!]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/the-post-most-of-you-have-been-waiting-for/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/the-post-most-of-you-have-been-waiting-for</id>
  <published>2019-08-16T20:57:00+13:00</published>
  <updated>2019-08-16T20:57:00+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;We’ve been a little quiet on the blog recently for various reasons. I wont go
into the reasons but lets just say it’s been interesting. That of course does
not mean that I haven’t been writing. On the contrary, I’ve written almost
30,000 words that I haven’t published yet. There’s a lot more to come, but it
hasn’t been appropriate to publish it just yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you follow us on Facebook then you know by now, that Annie and I have made
our first ocean passage. This will be an abridged account of that passage. While
it’s abridged, it’s a very long read. We will publish it in three parts over
three weeks. Those who support us on Patreon will get the whole piece
immediately as a thank you for supporting us. The rest of you, patience is
a virtue! You won’t be left out, it will just take a bit longer. Also good
things are worth waiting for right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the dream has been in the making for almost five years now, it’s been slow
going. We started planning this particular passage in January while we were
cruising in the Bay of Islands (I promise there’s something written about that
too). At the time we were considering going to New Caledonia, but abandoned that
idea after talking to many other cruisers who said they were heading to Tonga.
Also since we’re completely out of money (there’s another story there, and I’ve
written about that too), Tonga was the better option as we could do it with less
money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of things delayed us quite significantly.  I had a contract on the go
which was supposed to start at the end of January but for various reasons didn’t
materialize until we already left Westhaven marina, bound for Kauwau Island to
do a final refit in June. It got to the point where we just had to go or we
wouldn’t leave. An unplanned trip to Australia over Easter set us back a bit too
due to weather and my car got stolen from the marina parking lot (there’s
another story there, and yes I’ve also written about that), while we were away
in Australia.  So we then had to deal with the aftermath of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refitting took a bit longer than expected as we had to redo a significant amount
of fiberglass on Cheeky2 which we did not expect. There’s much to write about
the adventures here, especially when I let the smoke out of the compass (rookie
mistake, but a story for another time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took us far too long to get ready but eventually we managed to get on top of
all the jobs that had to be done at Kawau and we set off for the Bay of Islands.
This was to be our first overnight sail as we needed to experience it before the
main event (there’s another story there, but again not the one you’re here for
today). Lets just say that it took us two days instead of one and it was an
adventure which ended with us anchoring at 3 am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once in Opua we had a few minor things to take care of and some final
provisioning to do. We waited for a ‘good’ weather window so we could leave. We
had a fantastic time in Opua but we were happy to leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with everything we do, we’re not just content to have the normal or average
‘experience’. If we pay full price, we want the full ‘experience’. When you
reduce your equipment down to the essentials and nothing more you get a much
richer ‘experience’. What follows is an account of what happens when you set off
with that crazy mindset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further delay, lets get to the main event…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We checked out of Opua on Monday the 22nd of July at 10:30 am. It was
surprisingly easy. We had to leave the marina by midday. We’ve become incredibly
last minute when it comes to traveling and that bad habit has crept in the door
with passage making. Taleisin was not hundred percent put in order for an ocean
passage but the major things were done. While we were motoring out Annie was
still busy below stowing stuff properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B1N5un7H0jT/&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px;
box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px;
max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%;
width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B1N5un7H0jT/&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center;
text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex;
flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color:
#F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px;
width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column;
flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4;
border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width:
100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px;
flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:
19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px;
width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000,
-20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41
553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852
C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41
556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50
C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114
551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886
524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113
557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101
C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057
562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757
556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552
C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757
523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057
518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101
C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056
516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938
518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654
C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448
541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756
557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894
C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978
565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996
565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258
569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368
562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18
C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18
C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368
516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258
511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147
511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651
C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658
521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965
532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82
C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634
565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743
570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851
570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0;
font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal;
font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row;
margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color:
#F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform:
translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4;
height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px);
width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width:
12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4;
border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px
solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px)
translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid
transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color:
#F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform:
translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px
solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px)
translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0
4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B1N5un7H0jT/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000;
font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal;
font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;
word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Some snaps from our passage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px;
line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px
0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post
shared by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/svtaleisin/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd;
font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal;
font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; Annie Ryan&lt;/a&gt;
(@svtaleisin) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px;
line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2019-08-16T07:54:42+00:00&quot;&gt;Aug 16, 2019 at 12:54am
PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was very little wind and we knew it would be a slow start. After motoring
out into the bay we decided to take the new six horsepower outboard off (another
story to be told here), and stow it on the forward bunk to keep it safe while
out on the open ocean. This was much easier than anticipated and the water was
clam enough so that it wasn’t dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Annie had prepared a whole big pot of chicken soup which we planned on consuming
in the first 48 hours. This worked great for us on our first overnight passage
so we thought we’d stick with a winning formula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we had the outboard stowed below, Murphy paid a visit and the wind died
down completely. I had placed a Scopoderm patch behind my ear as soon as I felt
the slightest hint of seasickness. Unfortunately it didn’t work for me. That
first night I paid the lee rail two visits while Annie was sleeping down below.
Followed by another visit the following day. Annie was not feeling too good
either but held it together and looked after me as much as she could. We ended
up drifting and finding a few puffs of wind here and there. It took most of the
night to get away from New Zealand. I spent my watch laying in the cockpit with
my head on the deck box. I closed my eyes and opened them every five minutes or
so to scan the horizon. This would be the first few days of night watches for
me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we were finally away sailing for two days our InReach finally got activated
(this was a last minute addition, we got a secondhand one and there’s another
story here for later). Finally we were able to communicate with Bob McDavitt
regarding weather. Bob’s comment was, I was hoping you’d be further North by
now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On day three we encountered some heavy weather and decided to heave to. We did
it while there was still day light and got some rest while the rough stuff blew
past. Once Taleisin was hove to and we went down below, the change in motion of
the boat caused Annie to visit the lee rail. After my third visit I decided that
the Scopoderm was quite likely not working for me and removed it. I switched to
Sealegs but had to crush them in my mouth and hold it as long as I could to try
and get it absorbed into my body. That seemed to work rather well. The only
problem is I would be consuming them like tic-tacs for the rest of the voyage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the rough stuff passed we finally managed to get a nice day of sailing in.
We both felt better and were quite hungry. Annie said she felt like mashed
potato and disappeared down below. After some time she handed me a bowl of
mashed potato in the cockpit. I have to say that it was quite possibly the best
mashed potato I’ve had in my entire life. It could be that Annie had somehow
managed to produce the absolute best mashed potatoes the world has ever known or
it could be the fact that we’d hardly had anything to eat for three days due to
being seasick. I guess we’ll never know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Annie also produced some chicken tenders which we had on bread, I swear it was
fit for a king! We had a really nice sail for the entire day. Then things
started to pick up a bit. I sent a message to Bob asking what’s up with the
weather as he’d told us to sail North West until the wind shifts. Bob then
proceeded to route us clockwise around a low pressure system. Things just got
worse for us so we decided that we’d rather not continue to sail and heave to,
wait for it to pass and then hopefully we can ride the high pressure system that
was following. This time we had to do the procedure at night and we were much
better at it than the first time. Both times we put the para-anchor out as we
couldn’t stop Taleisin fore-reaching. The second blow was worse than the first,
but we managed to get going again sooner than the first time. At this stage we
were five days into the journey and had only managed to sail about two hundred
nautical miles from New Zealand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we got going again we entered a high pressure system and Bob told us to
sail North West until wind shifted. We had a fairly nice sail until we lost the
wind early in the morning the next day. This is when we noticed that our battery
wasn’t charging so there was something up with our solar panel that we lashed to
the dinghy. When we finally went to investigate we discovered that during all
the ‘drama’ the terminals got ripped clean off. The panel was flush with not so
much as a tiny bit of ribbon cable sticking up. We had another two panels down
below so we swapped them out and started thinking about how we could fix the
broken panel. It was a nice calm day with very little wind for the most part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that the other panel wasn’t charging the battery either so I went on
a troubleshooting spree. This involved me having to pull the battery out from
the mount I made and lashed it to. It was a rather involved process and it was
also quite hot. We were still dressed for the New Zealand winter as we hadn’t
had warm weather yet. As a result, I had sweat dripping from me at a rate that
made it look like I just stepped out of a shower. I did the only logical thing
and stripped down to just my underwear. After the appropriate amount of cussing
for a job of this description and a couple of false starts I managed to get
everything ticking over!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it was clam and I had an idea on how to fix the solar panel I decided to
give it a crack. In order to appreciate the moment I’ll try to describe the
scene. I’m sitting on the settee, just about stark naked, dripping in sweat. The
table folded open with the solar panel on top of it. I’m holding a Stanley knife
in one and and a flashlight in the other underneath the panel so I can see where
the ribbon cables are. I’m slowly trying to cut through the first layer of
plastic on the panel to reveal a bit of the cable so I can try to re-attach it.
After about fifteen minutes of struggling and cussing appropriately (I think
it’s mandatory to get jobs like this done, if you can’t do it due to having to
concentrate ask someone else to just stand there and cuss on your behalf; I think that will also help), I managed to get the three cables exposed enough
to deal to them. I spent a bit of time checking everything with my multi meter
to figure out what gets attached where.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still dripping with sweat and half naked, I dug out the little 150 watt inverter
and soldering iron (this was an impulse purchase but turned out to be extremely
useful). The boat was rocking since there wasn’t much wind but the swells were
at least consistent. Now I’m trying to balance the soldering iron on the table
while holding the required bits to solder on again. Luckily Annie came down to
hold things for me so I could solder the cables together. Looking at the mess
before me, I now had to somehow ensure it isn’t too vulnerable. Inspiration
struck when I realized that it was originally stuck down with 3M 5200 and
I happened to buy a tube of 5200 the day before we left. Just in case I needed
it. But the problem was holding it in place long enough for it to cure. The
terminal box doesn’t sit flat and the gap is now huge because of the three blobs
of solder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be continued…&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/the-post-most-of-you-have-been-waiting-for/&quot;&gt;Continue reading The post most of you have been waiting for! here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on August 16, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creating Adventures for Others]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/creating-adventures-for-others/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/creating-adventures-for-others</id>
  <published>2018-01-23T00:00:00+13:00</published>
  <updated>2018-01-23T00:00:00+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;We have been very fortunate over the  last few years with the opportunities that
have crossed  our path. Lin  has introduced us to  wonderful new friends  and we
have been  invited to  go along on  many wonderful adventures  (I still  have to
write about  many of  them). While  travelling in  the USA  we came  across many
people and we invited many  people to look us up if they were  to make it to New
Zealand. I recall saying to Annie that if  anybody does take us up on the offer,
and I doubt many will, I will make good on my promise to take them sailing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Brad/sailing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;leaving&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Copyright Campbell/Seamans&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/creating-adventures-for-others/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Creating Adventures for Others here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 23, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another Interview With Wooden Boat Dan]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/another-interview-with-wooden-boat-dan/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/another-interview-with-wooden-boat-dan</id>
  <published>2018-01-04T17:10:11+13:00</published>
  <updated>2018-01-04T17:10:11+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;It’s clearly a rainy day and we have nothing better to do…&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/another-interview-with-wooden-boat-dan/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Another Interview With Wooden Boat Dan here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 04, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changes and a New Way to Keep Up With Us]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/changes-and-a-new-way-to-keep-up-with-us/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/changes-and-a-new-way-to-keep-up-with-us</id>
  <published>2018-01-04T00:00:00+13:00</published>
  <updated>2018-01-04T00:00:00+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;I’m experiencing Deja  Vu, not that long  ago I broke the email  system. Today I
received another email about it not  working correctly. I do apologise for this!
I’ve added some more checks and controls to avoid this happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve received an empty email you can click through to the website and find
the last update in the archive section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I was making changes to the blogging system I decided to add a few
things.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/changes-and-a-new-way-to-keep-up-with-us/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Changes and a New Way to Keep Up With Us here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 04, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[In My Defence, I Was Left Unsupervised]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/in-my-defence-i-was-left-unsupervised/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/in-my-defence-i-was-left-unsupervised</id>
  <published>2018-01-03T19:21:14+13:00</published>
  <updated>2018-01-03T19:21:14+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Two posts in rapid succession… Something must be interesting…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can tell from the title, this is bound to be good!&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/in-my-defence-i-was-left-unsupervised/&quot;&gt;Continue reading In My Defence, I Was Left Unsupervised here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 03, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflections]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/reflections/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/reflections</id>
  <published>2017-12-31T16:00:54+13:00</published>
  <updated>2017-12-31T16:00:54+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;It’s been quite a  while since there’s been an update on  this blog. Rest assured
it’s not for lack of adventure, on the contrary, we’ve had too much!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve written quite a few blog posts, and they are long, very long and also quite
unfinished. Since they  are unfinished and not ready to  publish I’ve decided to
write something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I’m sitting in the Kawau boating club, waiting for the New Year’s eve
celebrations to start.  I’m looking out over the water  at Taleisin and thinking
back to the year that’s has been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/39399924801/&quot; title=&quot;Untitled&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4681/39399924801_f6e293ff98_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;429&quot; alt=&quot;Untitled&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/reflections/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Reflections here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on December 31, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Email Issues]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/email-issues/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/email-issues</id>
  <published>2017-05-07T07:49:50+13:00</published>
  <updated>2017-05-07T07:49:50+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;It would appear that I messed up  the email system with the last post. Hopefully
this issue will not re-occur in the  future since, I’ve added an automated check
before updating the blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If   you’re  not   technical  then   you  can   stop  reading   now  and   click
through   at   the  bottom   of   the   email   to   previous  post   or   click
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.taleisin.com/river-adventures/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/email-issues/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Email Issues here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on May 07, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[River Adventures]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/river-adventures/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/river-adventures</id>
  <published>2017-05-06T17:56:17+13:00</published>
  <updated>2017-05-06T17:56:17+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;A lot has happened since I’ve last written anything. This doesn’t mean that it’s
been boring…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the contrary, I’m not sure what  to write about since there’s so many awesome
adventures that we’ve had. The only logical  thing to do would be to write about
them in  the order they happened.  Given that watches and  calendars get ignored
aboard, we’ll just say that the following happened some time in February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We packed up the  possessions we wanted to keep and stored  them safely. We sold
everything worth selling and gave away  anything that we couldn’t sell. The rest
was sent off to the land fill. With the commitment made to live aboard full time
we got stuck  in the marina with some  bad weather. We had a date  to keep since
the CANANZ group were having a dinner  in Warkwarth and they were all planning a
cruise up the Mahurangi river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/32739029450/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Annie Hill&amp;#x27;s fantail. We met Bryan and Linda (the current owners) this weekend we enjoyed a nice visit and beer with the aboard taleisin this afternoon.&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/3/2883/32739029450_1bfefb79c9_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;534&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; alt=&quot;Annie Hill&amp;#x27;s fantail. We met Bryan and Linda (the current owners) this weekend we enjoyed a nice visit and beer with the aboard taleisin this afternoon.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/river-adventures/&quot;&gt;Continue reading River Adventures here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on May 06, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life Aboard Taleisin]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/life-aboard-taleisin/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/life-aboard-taleisin</id>
  <published>2017-02-16T10:16:07+13:00</published>
  <updated>2017-02-16T10:16:07+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since our last water based adventure. The reason we’ve been on
land for some time is so that we can avoid being on land for some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/32547798620/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Life aboard taleisin&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/4/3725/32547798620_bb3a55fdc7_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;Life aboard taleisin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me explain. It’s now been a week and a half since Taleisin has been our only
home.  We  spent the  last  month  sorting through  all  our  stuff and  selling
everything  that is  surplus  to  requirement. The  rest  was  put into  storage
awaiting our  return some day  in the future. We  got the smallest  storage unit
that we  could get away  with and  really only stored  things that we  wanted to
store. This was challenging as it  forced us to go through absolutely everything
we own to ensure we’re not paying to store junk.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/life-aboard-taleisin/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Life Aboard Taleisin here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on February 16, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Is It With Power Boats?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/what-is-it-with-power-boats/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/what-is-it-with-power-boats</id>
  <published>2017-01-18T19:31:07+13:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-18T19:31:07+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;I’ve been warned about this before,  cruising with a schedule doesn’t work. This
is more  true if you’re  sailing engine  less. While it’s  true that we  have an
outboard, we don’t carry that much petrol and when there’s a reasonable chop the
motor is not much use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We broke a  cardinal rule of cruising.  Whilst we’re both taking  a timeout from
work  at the  moment,  I’ve been  temporarily  sucked back  into  work for  some
important business deals to get closed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This unfortunate or  fortunate, depending on your perspective, fact  has lead to
us sailing back  to the marina in less than  favourable conditions. The schedule
dictated our  sailing day. Weather  plays an important  role in sailing  for us.
Since we’re still  learning we don’t like  to sail in conditions  that is beyond
our ability and comfort levels.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/what-is-it-with-power-boats/&quot;&gt;Continue reading What Is It With Power Boats? here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 18, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Never Miss Another Adventure]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/never-miss-another-adventure/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/never-miss-another-adventure</id>
  <published>2017-01-18T17:44:33+13:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-18T17:44:33+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;While this is not an adventure of  the nautical kind, I’ve just had an adventure
adding more dynamic content to a static  content only blog. If this doesn’t make
sense to you don’t worry about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing is that there’s now  a way for you to receive our adventures
directly via  email. While  this is not  my personal preference  I’ve had  a few
readers  ask for  this  feature.  Not wanting  to  disappoint  I quickly  hacked
something together to make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re one of the readers wanting to receive emails with our adventures, type
your email address in the box below and subscribe to our mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/never-miss-another-adventure/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Never Miss Another Adventure here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 18, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Small Adventures]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/small-adventures/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/small-adventures</id>
  <published>2017-01-12T19:37:26+14:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-12T19:37:26+14:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;When  you  own an  adventure  machine  like  Taleisin,  there’s no  shortage  of
adventures. After  our little adventure  with Taleisin  in Bon Accord  Harbor we
talked about the situation and what could have been done better. Sure, we didn’t
break  anything and  nobody got  injured,  but that  doesn’t mean  that we  were
comfortably in control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We discussed it with Lin, and she shed some light on what may have happened. Lin
suggested that  we take her little  12.5’ boat out for  a sail and go  and learn
what the winds do when you get closer to the headlands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While waiting for  a bit more suitable  weather as the wind was  blowing quite a
bit and it was really gusty too! We  just kicked back and relaxed. We did have a
day where we went walking on the other side of North Cove. It truly is a magical
island. It’s  not in any way  related to the  timeline we’re used to.  It really
feels like  time has moved on  and this little island  is stuck in the  past. We
absolutely love this place!&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/small-adventures/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Small Adventures here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 12, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rookie Mistake]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/rookie-mistake/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/rookie-mistake</id>
  <published>2017-01-08T19:33:23+14:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-08T19:33:23+14:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;With the weather  turning and the anchorage getting less  comfortable we decided
to  find a  better spot.  We spent  the  last few  days carrying  water back  to
Taleisin. We did it the hard way, we  carried 20 Litre water cans back and forth
for a  total of  4 trips. We  rowed back and  forth and  loaded it all  on board
Taleisin. Yes we probably could have motored up to the dock and done it all very
quickly. That all sounded  too easy so we did it the hard  way. We got some good
exercise and I’m sure we’re better off because of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We  got Taleisin  ready to  sail  this morning.  We checked  and double  checked
everything. We put  a reef in the  main as it’s blowing around  17 knots gusting
into the  20’s. We  hoisted the main,  but didn’t cleat  the sheet  off. Feeling
confident we started to winch the anchor in, it’s a tough job if you’re not used
to it. I feel  like we’ll be better off physically in the  long run doing things
this way, rather than  the alternative. Time will tell if this gets easier or
more painful…&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/rookie-mistake/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Rookie Mistake here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 08, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Off Grid]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/off-grid/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/off-grid</id>
  <published>2017-01-06T21:12:58+14:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-06T21:12:58+14:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;We’re back floating! The last couple of days have been fairly laid back, sure we
did  some work  on Taleisin.  Double  checking the  hull is  clean, making  sure
everything is removed behind the rudder. She’s looking pretty sweet! While I was
at it,  I got Lin  to supervise me  replacing the Sikaflex  on a few  small deck
seams. Whilst  it’s not rocket  science, there was a  few things I  didn’t know.
It’s always silly  in my eyes to not  learn from those around you  before you go
experimenting and  trying to work  out how to  do something that’s  already been
done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/32135639085/&quot; title=&quot;Off grid&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c6.staticflickr.com/1/658/32135639085_49dd06f5bd_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;Off grid&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/off-grid/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Off Grid here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 06, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back on the Grid]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/back-on-the-grid/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/back-on-the-grid</id>
  <published>2017-01-04T08:41:34+14:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-04T08:41:34+14:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Back on the tidal  grid! Since Taleisin is home and she still  fits on the tidal
grid at Lin’s we decided that it would be a good idea to give the bottom a clean
and inspect the seacock that’s been giving me grief as of late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/31241590584/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Untitled&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/294/31241590584_5eeb16ef27_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;Untitled&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got  the motor  going and  took Taleisin for  a trip  around the  bay, mostly
because the wind was blowing and we weren’t comfortable taking the direct route.
We navigated our way through all the moored boats and slowly made our way to the
jetty.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/back-on-the-grid/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Back on the Grid here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 04, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Baking Bread]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/baking-bread/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/baking-bread</id>
  <published>2017-01-02T18:45:19+14:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-02T18:45:19+14:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Today I baked  a loaf of bread. Very  exciting, I know. It’s been  almost a week
since we consumed our  last bread and I’ve been promising Annie  that I’d bake a
loaf of bread. It’s something I used to do a few years ago so the concept is not
new to me. How ever I’ve never done it all by hand without electricity. It’s not
rocket science to bake bread. Yeast, a bit  of sugar, water and flour with a bit
of salt will be the job done. Use a bit of elbow grease and it’s not long before
you have something that resembles dough.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/baking-bread/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Baking Bread here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 02, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interview - Hooked on Wooden Boats]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/interview-hooked-on-wooden-boats/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/interview-hooked-on-wooden-boats</id>
  <published>2017-01-01T11:09:36+14:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-01T11:09:36+14:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Looking at the  date, 2016 is finally over.  I believe a lot of  people would be
happy to see the back of 2016. Happy New Year, may 2017 be a good one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year when we were at the wooden  boat festival we did an interview with Dan
Mattson.  It was  a bit  of fun  and  Dan has  just sent  me the  word that  the
interview is up on his pod cast. If you’re curious have a listen
&lt;a href=&quot;http://hookedonwoodenboats.com/howb-191-interview-eben-bruyus-and-annie-ryan-on-acquiring-famed-cutter-taleisin-from-the-pardeys/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re still hanging out  in North Cove, we got invited to a  small new years eve
gathering with  the locals. We had  a great time and  got to see parts  of North
Cove we’ve never seen before. This place  is magical. When we head over that way
again I’ll  be sure to take  some pictures. Thank  you to all the  residents for
making our time here very pleasurable!&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/interview-hooked-on-wooden-boats/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Interview - Hooked on Wooden Boats here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 01, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dinner Is Served]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/dinner-is-served/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/dinner-is-served</id>
  <published>2016-12-30T21:29:40+14:00</published>
  <updated>2016-12-30T21:29:40+14:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Annie prepared  this magnificent meal  on board  Taleisin tonight. It  tasted as
good as it looks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/31937747516/&quot; title=&quot;Dinner is served&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c5.staticflickr.com/1/433/31937747516_482ef6b63e_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;Dinner is served&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After  a bit  of trial  and error  we figured  out how  to use  the oven  aboard
Taleisin. We did of  course have the benefit of being on a  mooring just a short
row from Lin’s door step. Lin is  always very helpful and knows everything about
anything aboard Taleisin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been  having a great time  in North Cove.  Lin invited us over  for dinner
along with the family on the French yacht next to us. Lin served what could only
be described as the best salmon I’ve  ever had. Everything is always lovely when
you’re over  for dinner at  the Pardey’s.  The company is  good and the  food is
always excellent!&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/dinner-is-served/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Dinner Is Served here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hanging Out in North Cove]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/hanging-out-in-north-cove/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/hanging-out-in-north-cove</id>
  <published>2016-12-28T20:10:05+14:00</published>
  <updated>2016-12-28T20:10:05+14:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;We turned in  early last night, we  were both absolutely exhausted.  As an added
bonus we slept in this morning too. It’s  not like we have somewhere to be!? The
plan was to move Taleisin to a mooring closer to Lin’s place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we  finally decided to  wake up we  went on deck  and the cove  was nearly
empty. We were trying  to figure out which mooring we were  supposed to pick up.
After a bit of back and forth Annie suggested that we row over and check it out,
even tough it would be a right pain to row back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were busy trying to get Cheeky off the cabin top a friendly sailor came
along side in a kayak and introduced herself.  We invited her on board for a bit
of a chat as it was quite choppy in  the spot we anchored. It turns out that her
boat was on the mooring next to the one  we were moving to. We asked her if she’d
mind helping us move. She was a real sport and jumped to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/31120073253/&quot; title=&quot;Hanging out in north cove&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c6.staticflickr.com/1/452/31120073253_585b6795bd_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;Hanging out in north cove&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/hanging-out-in-north-cove/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Hanging Out in North Cove here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on December 28, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
