<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Taleisin - Adventure Machine!</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000" />
<updated>2018-01-07T16:24:32+13:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
<author>
  <name></name>
  <uri>http://localhost:4000/</uri>
  
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Another Interview With Wooden Boat Dan]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/another-interview-with-wooden-boat-dan/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/another-interview-with-wooden-boat-dan</id>
  <published>2018-01-04T17:10:11+13:00</published>
  <updated>2018-01-04T17:10:11+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;It’s clearly a rainy day and we have nothing better to do…&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/another-interview-with-wooden-boat-dan/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Another Interview With Wooden Boat Dan here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 04, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changes and a New Way to Keep Up With Us]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/changes-and-a-new-way-to-keep-up-with-us/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/changes-and-a-new-way-to-keep-up-with-us</id>
  <published>2018-01-04T00:00:00+13:00</published>
  <updated>2018-01-04T00:00:00+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;I’m experiencing Deja  Vu, not that long  ago I broke the email  system. Today I
received another email about it not  working correctly. I do apologise for this!
I’ve added some more checks and controls to avoid this happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve received an empty email you can click through to the website and find
the last update in the archive section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I was making changes to the blogging system I decided to add a few
things.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/changes-and-a-new-way-to-keep-up-with-us/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Changes and a New Way to Keep Up With Us here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 04, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[In My Defence, I Was Left Unsupervised]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/in-my-defence-i-was-left-unsupervised/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/in-my-defence-i-was-left-unsupervised</id>
  <published>2018-01-03T19:21:14+13:00</published>
  <updated>2018-01-03T19:21:14+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Two posts in rapid succession… Something must be interesting…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can tell from the title, this is bound to be good!&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/in-my-defence-i-was-left-unsupervised/&quot;&gt;Continue reading In My Defence, I Was Left Unsupervised here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 03, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflections]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/reflections/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/reflections</id>
  <published>2017-12-31T16:00:54+13:00</published>
  <updated>2017-12-31T16:00:54+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;It’s been quite a  while since there’s been an update on  this blog. Rest assured
it’s not for lack of adventure, on the contrary, we’ve had too much!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve written quite a few blog posts, and they are long, very long and also quite
unfinished. Since they  are unfinished and not ready to  publish I’ve decided to
write something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I’m sitting in the Kawau boating club, waiting for the New Year’s eve
celebrations to start.  I’m looking out over the water  at Taleisin and thinking
back to the year that’s has been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/39399924801/&quot; title=&quot;Untitled&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://farm5.staticflickr.com/4681/39399924801_f6e293ff98_z.jpg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;429&quot; alt=&quot;Untitled&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/reflections/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Reflections here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on December 31, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Email Issues]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/email-issues/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/email-issues</id>
  <published>2017-05-07T06:49:50+12:00</published>
  <updated>2017-05-07T06:49:50+12:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;It would appear that I messed up  the email system with the last post. Hopefully
this issue will not re-occur in the  future since, I’ve added an automated check
before updating the blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If   you’re  not   technical  then   you  can   stop  reading   now  and   click
through   at   the  bottom   of   the   email   to   previous  post   or   click
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.taleisin.com/river-adventures/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/email-issues/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Email Issues here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on May 07, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[River Adventures]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/river-adventures/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/river-adventures</id>
  <published>2017-05-06T16:56:17+12:00</published>
  <updated>2017-05-06T16:56:17+12:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;A lot has happened since I’ve last written anything. This doesn’t mean that it’s
been boring…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the contrary, I’m not sure what  to write about since there’s so many awesome
adventures that we’ve had. The only logical  thing to do would be to write about
them in  the order they happened.  Given that watches and  calendars get ignored
aboard, we’ll just say that the following happened some time in February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We packed up the  possessions we wanted to keep and stored  them safely. We sold
everything worth selling and gave away  anything that we couldn’t sell. The rest
was sent off to the land fill. With the commitment made to live aboard full time
we got stuck  in the marina with some  bad weather. We had a date  to keep since
the CANANZ group were having a dinner  in Warkwarth and they were all planning a
cruise up the Mahurangi river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/32739029450/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Annie Hill&amp;#x27;s fantail. We met Bryan and Linda (the current owners) this weekend we enjoyed a nice visit and beer with the aboard taleisin this afternoon.&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/3/2883/32739029450_1bfefb79c9_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;534&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; alt=&quot;Annie Hill&amp;#x27;s fantail. We met Bryan and Linda (the current owners) this weekend we enjoyed a nice visit and beer with the aboard taleisin this afternoon.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/river-adventures/&quot;&gt;Continue reading River Adventures here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on May 06, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life Aboard Taleisin]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/life-aboard-taleisin/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/life-aboard-taleisin</id>
  <published>2017-02-16T10:16:07+13:00</published>
  <updated>2017-02-16T10:16:07+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;It’s been a while since our last water based adventure. The reason we’ve been on
land for some time is so that we can avoid being on land for some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/32547798620/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;Life aboard taleisin&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/4/3725/32547798620_bb3a55fdc7_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;Life aboard taleisin&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me explain. It’s now been a week and a half since Taleisin has been our only
home.  We  spent the  last  month  sorting through  all  our  stuff and  selling
everything  that is  surplus  to  requirement. The  rest  was  put into  storage
awaiting our  return some day  in the future. We  got the smallest  storage unit
that we  could get away  with and  really only stored  things that we  wanted to
store. This was challenging as it  forced us to go through absolutely everything
we own to ensure we’re not paying to store junk.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/life-aboard-taleisin/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Life Aboard Taleisin here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on February 16, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Is It With Power Boats?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/what-is-it-with-power-boats/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/what-is-it-with-power-boats</id>
  <published>2017-01-18T19:31:07+13:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-18T19:31:07+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;I’ve been warned about this before,  cruising with a schedule doesn’t work. This
is more  true if you’re  sailing engine  less. While it’s  true that we  have an
outboard, we don’t carry that much petrol and when there’s a reasonable chop the
motor is not much use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We broke a  cardinal rule of cruising.  Whilst we’re both taking  a timeout from
work  at the  moment,  I’ve been  temporarily  sucked back  into  work for  some
important business deals to get closed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This unfortunate or  fortunate, depending on your perspective, fact  has lead to
us sailing back  to the marina in less than  favourable conditions. The schedule
dictated our  sailing day. Weather  plays an important  role in sailing  for us.
Since we’re still  learning we don’t like  to sail in conditions  that is beyond
our ability and comfort levels.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/what-is-it-with-power-boats/&quot;&gt;Continue reading What Is It With Power Boats? here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 18, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Never Miss Another Adventure]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/never-miss-another-adventure/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/never-miss-another-adventure</id>
  <published>2017-01-18T17:44:33+13:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-18T17:44:33+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;While this is not an adventure of  the nautical kind, I’ve just had an adventure
adding more dynamic content to a static  content only blog. If this doesn’t make
sense to you don’t worry about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing is that there’s now  a way for you to receive our adventures
directly via  email. While  this is not  my personal preference  I’ve had  a few
readers  ask for  this  feature.  Not wanting  to  disappoint  I quickly  hacked
something together to make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re one of the readers wanting to receive emails with our adventures, type
your email address in the box below and subscribe to our mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/never-miss-another-adventure/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Never Miss Another Adventure here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 18, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Small Adventures]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/small-adventures/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/small-adventures</id>
  <published>2017-01-12T18:37:26+13:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-12T18:37:26+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;When  you  own an  adventure  machine  like  Taleisin,  there’s no  shortage  of
adventures. After  our little adventure  with Taleisin  in Bon Accord  Harbor we
talked about the situation and what could have been done better. Sure, we didn’t
break  anything and  nobody got  injured,  but that  doesn’t mean  that we  were
comfortably in control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We discussed it with Lin, and she shed some light on what may have happened. Lin
suggested that  we take her little  12.5’ boat out for  a sail and go  and learn
what the winds do when you get closer to the headlands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While waiting for  a bit more suitable  weather as the wind was  blowing quite a
bit and it was really gusty too! We  just kicked back and relaxed. We did have a
day where we went walking on the other side of North Cove. It truly is a magical
island. It’s  not in any way  related to the  timeline we’re used to.  It really
feels like  time has moved on  and this little island  is stuck in the  past. We
absolutely love this place!&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/small-adventures/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Small Adventures here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 12, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rookie Mistake]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/rookie-mistake/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/rookie-mistake</id>
  <published>2017-01-08T18:33:23+13:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-08T18:33:23+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;With the weather  turning and the anchorage getting less  comfortable we decided
to  find a  better spot.  We spent  the  last few  days carrying  water back  to
Taleisin. We did it the hard way, we  carried 20 Litre water cans back and forth
for a  total of  4 trips. We  rowed back and  forth and  loaded it all  on board
Taleisin. Yes we probably could have motored up to the dock and done it all very
quickly. That all sounded  too easy so we did it the hard  way. We got some good
exercise and I’m sure we’re better off because of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We  got Taleisin  ready to  sail  this morning.  We checked  and double  checked
everything. We put  a reef in the  main as it’s blowing around  17 knots gusting
into the  20’s. We  hoisted the main,  but didn’t cleat  the sheet  off. Feeling
confident we started to winch the anchor in, it’s a tough job if you’re not used
to it. I feel  like we’ll be better off physically in the  long run doing things
this way, rather than  the alternative. Time will tell if this gets easier or
more painful…&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/rookie-mistake/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Rookie Mistake here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 08, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Off Grid]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/off-grid/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/off-grid</id>
  <published>2017-01-06T20:12:58+13:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-06T20:12:58+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;We’re back floating! The last couple of days have been fairly laid back, sure we
did  some work  on Taleisin.  Double  checking the  hull is  clean, making  sure
everything is removed behind the rudder. She’s looking pretty sweet! While I was
at it,  I got Lin  to supervise me  replacing the Sikaflex  on a few  small deck
seams. Whilst  it’s not rocket  science, there was a  few things I  didn’t know.
It’s always silly  in my eyes to not  learn from those around you  before you go
experimenting and  trying to work  out how to  do something that’s  already been
done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/32135639085/&quot; title=&quot;Off grid&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c6.staticflickr.com/1/658/32135639085_49dd06f5bd_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;Off grid&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/off-grid/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Off Grid here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 06, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Back on the Grid]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/back-on-the-grid/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/back-on-the-grid</id>
  <published>2017-01-04T07:41:34+13:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-04T07:41:34+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Back on the tidal  grid! Since Taleisin is home and she still  fits on the tidal
grid at Lin’s we decided that it would be a good idea to give the bottom a clean
and inspect the seacock that’s been giving me grief as of late.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/31241590584/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Untitled&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/294/31241590584_5eeb16ef27_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;Untitled&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We got  the motor  going and  took Taleisin for  a trip  around the  bay, mostly
because the wind was blowing and we weren’t comfortable taking the direct route.
We navigated our way through all the moored boats and slowly made our way to the
jetty.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/back-on-the-grid/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Back on the Grid here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 04, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Baking Bread]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/baking-bread/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/baking-bread</id>
  <published>2017-01-02T17:45:19+13:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-02T17:45:19+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Today I baked  a loaf of bread. Very  exciting, I know. It’s been  almost a week
since we consumed our  last bread and I’ve been promising Annie  that I’d bake a
loaf of bread. It’s something I used to do a few years ago so the concept is not
new to me. How ever I’ve never done it all by hand without electricity. It’s not
rocket science to bake bread. Yeast, a bit  of sugar, water and flour with a bit
of salt will be the job done. Use a bit of elbow grease and it’s not long before
you have something that resembles dough.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/baking-bread/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Baking Bread here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 02, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Interview - Hooked on Wooden Boats]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/interview-hooked-on-wooden-boats/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/interview-hooked-on-wooden-boats</id>
  <published>2017-01-01T10:09:36+13:00</published>
  <updated>2017-01-01T10:09:36+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Looking at the  date, 2016 is finally over.  I believe a lot of  people would be
happy to see the back of 2016. Happy New Year, may 2017 be a good one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year when we were at the wooden  boat festival we did an interview with Dan
Mattson.  It was  a bit  of fun  and  Dan has  just sent  me the  word that  the
interview is up on his pod cast. If you’re curious have a listen
&lt;a href=&quot;http://hookedonwoodenboats.com/howb-191-interview-eben-bruyus-and-annie-ryan-on-acquiring-famed-cutter-taleisin-from-the-pardeys/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re still hanging out  in North Cove, we got invited to a  small new years eve
gathering with  the locals. We had  a great time and  got to see parts  of North
Cove we’ve never seen before. This place  is magical. When we head over that way
again I’ll  be sure to take  some pictures. Thank  you to all the  residents for
making our time here very pleasurable!&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/interview-hooked-on-wooden-boats/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Interview - Hooked on Wooden Boats here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on January 01, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dinner Is Served]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/dinner-is-served/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/dinner-is-served</id>
  <published>2016-12-30T20:29:40+13:00</published>
  <updated>2016-12-30T20:29:40+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Annie prepared  this magnificent meal  on board  Taleisin tonight. It  tasted as
good as it looks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/31937747516/&quot; title=&quot;Dinner is served&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c5.staticflickr.com/1/433/31937747516_482ef6b63e_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;Dinner is served&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After  a bit  of trial  and error  we figured  out how  to use  the oven  aboard
Taleisin. We did of  course have the benefit of being on a  mooring just a short
row from Lin’s door step. Lin is  always very helpful and knows everything about
anything aboard Taleisin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been  having a great time  in North Cove.  Lin invited us over  for dinner
along with the family on the French yacht next to us. Lin served what could only
be described as the best salmon I’ve  ever had. Everything is always lovely when
you’re over  for dinner at  the Pardey’s.  The company is  good and the  food is
always excellent!&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/dinner-is-served/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Dinner Is Served here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on December 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hanging Out in North Cove]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/hanging-out-in-north-cove/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/hanging-out-in-north-cove</id>
  <published>2016-12-28T19:10:05+13:00</published>
  <updated>2016-12-28T19:10:05+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;We turned in  early last night, we  were both absolutely exhausted.  As an added
bonus we slept in this morning too. It’s  not like we have somewhere to be!? The
plan was to move Taleisin to a mooring closer to Lin’s place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we  finally decided to  wake up we  went on deck  and the cove  was nearly
empty. We were trying  to figure out which mooring we were  supposed to pick up.
After a bit of back and forth Annie suggested that we row over and check it out,
even tough it would be a right pain to row back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were busy trying to get Cheeky off the cabin top a friendly sailor came
along side in a kayak and introduced herself.  We invited her on board for a bit
of a chat as it was quite choppy in  the spot we anchored. It turns out that her
boat was on the mooring next to the one  we were moving to. We asked her if she’d
mind helping us move. She was a real sport and jumped to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/31120073253/&quot; title=&quot;Hanging out in north cove&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c6.staticflickr.com/1/452/31120073253_585b6795bd_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;Hanging out in north cove&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/hanging-out-in-north-cove/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Hanging Out in North Cove here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on December 28, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Return to North Cove]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/return-to-north-cove/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/return-to-north-cove</id>
  <published>2016-12-27T19:27:34+13:00</published>
  <updated>2016-12-27T19:27:34+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Our original  plan was  to sail to  North Cove yesterday.  But the  winds didn’t
co-operate, instead we motored all day and tucked in for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it turns out  that it was quite a bouncy anchorage,  easily corrected with a
snubber off  the bowsprit. Whilst  this didn’t stop the  bounce it made  it more
than habitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning I said to Annie, “I want to sail off the anchor!”. We had the motor
in neutral, just in  case. I  prepared Taleisin for  sailing while  Annie cooked
breakfast. After we finished eating and  putting Taleisin in order down below we
winched in the anchor until we were just  about ready to lift it. We hoisted the
stays’l. Annie grabbed the tiller and when  the anchor was up she sheeted in the
stays’l. We were off without a hitch! I hoisted the main and the jib while Annie
slowly sailed us out of the anchorage. It was a nice start to the day.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/return-to-north-cove/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Return to North Cove here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on December 27, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Escape]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/escape/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/escape</id>
  <published>2016-12-26T17:10:15+13:00</published>
  <updated>2016-12-26T17:10:15+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;This might be  the post most of  the people following this little  blog has been
waiting for. Well maybe, we’re not heading  off shore, but we have cast the dock
lines off  for the  time being.  We’ve got  the boat  provisioned and  we’re out
playing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be a little longer than  the previous weekend cruise we did (I haven’t
written about it yet, but it was  great). We’re currently sitting at anchor in a
small bay called Okoromai (Shakespeare) Bay.  We’re the only boat anchored here,
and there might be a reason for that we’re not sure yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our  plan  was to  sail  to  Kawau  Island today,  but  there  was no  wind,  so
unfortunately we had to use the noisy  outboard motor to get away from the dock.
The bottom line is that we’re out, away from the dock and we’re sailing! Well we
will be! We’ve decided to hang out in this little bay until the wind picks up so
we can continue our little journey to Kawau Island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s not much to  say about the adventure today as  it was rather uneventful.
We managed  to leave the marina  just fine, which of  course is a huge  bonus as
we’ve not had the best of luck with marina adventures to date! We managed to get
a  bit of  sailing done  in  the harbour  but  then the  winds died  completely.
Motoring is not fun  and we didn’t really care for it. It  was really a means to
an end,  now that we’ve left  the doc we don’t  feel the pressure of  needing to
leave. That part is done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that we’ve been  so busy with the run up to Christmas  we’re both tired so
now  it’s time  to rest  and recover  from all  the stress  we’ve placed  on our
bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are  some pictures  of the  little anchorage we’re  in. We’re  anchored in
about 4.5 meters of water and so far it would seem like a calm quite anchorage!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/31763627521/&quot; title=&quot;Escape&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c2.staticflickr.com/1/368/31763627521_821a659ba6_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;Escape&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/31070853873/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Escape&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c2.staticflickr.com/1/526/31070853873_0d6be758ed_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;Escape&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/31842745676/in/photostream/&quot; title=&quot;Escape&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c5.staticflickr.com/1/256/31842745676_8f8bfd1573_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;Escape&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/31763620081/&quot; title=&quot;Escape&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c2.staticflickr.com/1/339/31763620081_3842fd3f3c_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;Escape&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/escape/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Escape here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on December 26, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Port Townsend Wooden Boat Festival 2016]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/port-townsend-wooden-boat-festival-2016/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/port-townsend-wooden-boat-festival-2016</id>
  <published>2016-10-31T16:08:31+13:00</published>
  <updated>2016-10-31T16:08:31+13:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Our  recent status  as  wooden boat  owners  has  opened up  many  new doors  to
interested and exciting  opportunities. We are not only new  to wooden boats but
to boats and sailing itself. One evening after completing one of many boat tasks
I gave  Lin Pardey a call  to share my  experiences. Lin suggested that  we come
along to the  wooden boat festival in Port Townsend  Washington State, USA. This
presented numerous challenges concerning work for  both Annie and myself. When I
got home that evening I told Annie about this random spur of the moment idea and
we decided that life is too short, screw it - lets do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/30222678904/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSC_6140&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c1.staticflickr.com/6/5692/30222678904_d7ccb6bd84_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;531&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_6140&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/sdki/30738394322/in/dateposted-public/&quot; title=&quot;DSC_6117&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://c3.staticflickr.com/6/5464/30738394322_9250be565e_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;531&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_6117&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/port-townsend-wooden-boat-festival-2016/&quot;&gt;Continue reading Port Townsend Wooden Boat Festival 2016 here.&lt;/a&gt; Originally published by  at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Taleisin - Adventure Machine!&lt;/a&gt; on October 31, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
